Friedlander, Walter A.; Papers ger003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence files, 1918-1984; 2; 3,383 folders
  - Correspondence with groups and organizations, 1933-1984; 2.4; 301 folders, approx. 2635 items of correspondence
    - Environmental Task Force, Undated (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 90)
    - European American Students Club, 1969 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 91)
    - European Centre for Social Welfare Training and Research (Helga Nowotny), 1978-1982 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 92)
      See also Vienna Institute for Development.
    - Evangelische Akademie Arnolshain, 1979-1980 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 93)
    - Family Service of Berkeley, 1972 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 94)
    - Farmworkers Justice Fund, 1983 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 95)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1979 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 96)
    - Find Me, Inc., 1982 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 97)
    - First Congregational Church, Berkeley, 1957 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 98)
    - The Ford Foundation, 1958 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 99)
    - Forum for Contemporary History, Undated (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 100)
    - * The Fourth World, Undated
      See International Movement A.T.D., The Fourth World
    - Free China Relief Association (Ku Cheng-kang), 1975 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 101)
    - Freiburg, Seminar für Sozialarbeit, 1973 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 102)
    - Freie Universität, Berlin, 1967-1969 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 103)
    - Friedrich Ebert Stiftung (Horst Heidermann), 1974-1981 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 104)
    - Friends of Danilo Dolci, inc, 1962-1982 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 105)
    - Friends of Europe, Undated (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 106)
      See also Smith, Rennie.
    - Friends of German Freedom (Mary Fox), 1937-1939 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 107)
    - Friends of the Earth/Marin-Sonoma, 1980 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 108)
    - Fulbright Commission, 1962-1969 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 109)
    - Fund for an Open Society, 1984 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 110)
    - German-American Committee for Spanish Relief (Deutsch-Amerikanisches Hilfskomitee zur Unterstützung des spanischen Freiheitskampfes), 1938 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 111)
    - German-American League for Culture, Chicago (Deutschamerikanischer Kulturverband; Erich von Schroetter), 1937-1940 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 112)
    - German-American Relief Committee for Victims of Fascism (Deutsch-Amerikanisches Hilfskomitee für die Opfer des Faschismus), 1940 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 113)
    - German Information Center, 1971-1977 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 114)
    - German Jewish Aid Committee, 1939 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 115)
    - Gray Panthers Project Fund, 1983-1984 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 116)
    - Hauptjugendamt Berlin, 1954 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 117)
    - Hebrew Sheltering and Immigrant Aid Society of America, 1939 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 118)
    - Historische Kommission zu Berlin, 1973-1974 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 119)
    - The Holocaust Library and Research Center of San Francisco, 1980-1983 (Box 22 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 120)
    - Home for Jewish Parents, 1978 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 121)
    - Hong Kong Discharged Prisoners' Aid Society, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 122)
    - Hull House Association, 1974-1976 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 123)
    - Human Assistance Programs (HAP), Inc., 1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 124)
    - Humanitas International, Undated (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 125)
    - Independent Action, 1981 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 126)
    - Institut für soziale Arbeit e.V., 1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 127)
    - Institut für soziales Design, 1981-1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 128)
    - Institute for Democratic Socialism, 1981-1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 129)
    - Institute for the Study of Conscious Evolution, 1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 130)
    - Inter-University European Institute on Social Welfare, 1978 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 131)
    - International Association for Community Development, 1980-1981 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 132)
    - International Association of Schools of Social Work, 1960-1984 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 133)
    - International Conference of Social Work, 1952-1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 134)
    - International Council on Social Welfare (Reuben C. Baetz, Joe R. Hoffer, Kate Katzki, Kenneth Kindelsperger, John MacDonald, Rudolf Pense), 1969-1984 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 135)
    - International Ecology University (I.E.U), Undated (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 136)
    - International Federation of Social Workers, 1974 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 137)
    - International Institute of the East Bay, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 138)
    - International Movement, A.T.D., The Fourth World (Fanchette Clement-Fanelli), 1979-1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 139)
    - The International Platform Association, 1968-1980 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 140)
    - International Rescue and Relief Committee/International Rescue Committee (Eva Lewinski, Sheba Strunsky), 1942-1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 141)
    - International Social Security Association, 1980 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 142)
    - International Society for Community Development, 1969-1980 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 143)
    - International Society for the Welfare of Cripples, 1956 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 144)
    - International Sociological Association, 1980 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 145)
    - International Stamp Club, Undated (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 146)
    - International Student Club of America, 1969 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 147)
    - International Union for Child Welfare, 1962-1971 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 148)
    - Internationales Institut für Medien und Entwicklung/International Institute for Media and Development, 1978 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 149)
    - Intertribal Friendship House, 1971 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 150)
    - Israeli Association of Social Workers, 1978 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 151)
    - Jewish Club of 1933, 1977 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 152)
    - Jewish Public Relations Council, 1945; 1977 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 153)
    - John Woolman School, 1964; 1978 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 154)
    - Joint Committee on International Social Work of Northern California, 1952-1953 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 155)
    - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, 1959 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 156)
    - Jugendamt Düsseldorf, 1981 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 157)
    - Kölnische Gesellschaft für christlich-jüdische Zusammenarbeit, 1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 158)
    - Korean Relief, Inc., 1974 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 159)
    - KPFA (radio station), 1955-1963 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 160)
    - KQED (TV station), 1970-1981 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 161)
    - Krohn-Rhodes Research Institute, Inc., 1967 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 162)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1937; Undated (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 163)
    - Leo Baeck Institute, 1962-1966 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 164)
    - Livingston, David, Foundation, 1974 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 165)
    - London Institute for Applied Research, Undated (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 166)
    - MASS, 1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 167)
    - The Menninger Foundation, 1965; 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 168)
    - Mental Hygiene Society of Northern California, 1945 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 169)
    - Michigan State University, 1959; 1972 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 170)
    - Middle East Institute, 1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 171)
    - Middlebury College, 1966 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 172)
    - Minnesota Welfare Association, 1965 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 173)
    - Missing Persons & Violent Crime Victims, 1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 174)
    - The Montclair-Greater Oakland Democratic Club, 1982-1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 175)
    - MRI (Mental Research Institute), 1974 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 176)
    - Mütterschutzverband unehelicher Besatzungskinder in Deutschland e.V. (Luis Jedelhauser), 1955 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 177)
    - National Assembly for Social Policy and Development, Inc., 1973 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 178)
    - National Association of Counties (NACo), 1977 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 179)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1958-1964 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 180)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1965-1966 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 181)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1967 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 182)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1968 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 183)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1969 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 184)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1970 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 185)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1971 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 186)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1972-1974 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 187)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1975-1980 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 188)
    - National Association of Social Workers (National and Golden Gate Chapter), 1981-1984 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 189)
    - National Committee on Employment of Youth, 1963 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 190)
    - National Conference of Social Work / National Conference on Social Welfare (Joe R. Hoffer), 1946-1963 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 191)
    - National Conference on Social Welfare (Joe R. Hoffer), 1964 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 192)
    - National Conference on Social Welfare (Joe R. Hoffer), 1965-1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 193)
    - * National Coordinating Committee For Aid to Refugees and Emigrants Coming From Germany, Undated
    - National Federation of Settlements and Neighborhood Centers, 1963 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 194)
    - National Indian Youth Council, Inc., 1976 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 195)
    - National Institute of Mental Health, 1981 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 196)
    - National Sharecroppers Fund, 1965 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 197)
    - Nationalkomittee für seelische Gesundheit, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 198)
    - NATO Commission on Changes of Modern Society, 1978 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 199)
    - Neighborhood House (E. P. "Red" Stephenson), 1957-1965 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 200)
    - Neue Erziehung e.V., 1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 201)
    - New America, 1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 202)
    - The Northbrae Woman's Club, 1970 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 203)
    - Northern California Ecumentical Council, 1978 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 204)
    - Northern California Service League, 1969-1971 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 205)
    - Notgemeinschaft Deutscher Wissenschaftler im Ausland (F. Demuth), 1934-1937 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 206)
    - Oakland Symphony, 1980 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 207)
    - Olympic Games, 1975 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 208)
    - Oxfam America, Undated (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 209)
    - PACE (Political Action for Candidate Election), 1978-1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 210)
    - The Pacific Sociological Society, 1960-1980 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 211)
    - Pallotine Missionaries, 1974 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 212)
    - Peace & Social Action Council, 1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 213)
    - People's Development Program/Peoples Voices (Jim Bernard), 1968-1972 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 214)
    - People's Peace (Ernest Caldecott), 1947-1948 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 215)
    - Planned Parenthood, 1972 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 216)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- general, 1981-1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 217)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- Austria, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 218)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- England, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 219)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- Germany (Bundeszusammenschluß für Straffälligenhilfe), 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 220)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- India, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 221)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- Kenya, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 222)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- The Netherlands, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 223)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- New Zealand, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 224)
    - Prisoner's Aid -- Switzerland, 1979 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 225)
    - Pro Familia (Anna Luise Prager), 1976 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 226)
    - Pro Seneosute, 1984 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 227)
    - Prospect Park Co-op, 1963-1965 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 228)
    - Project HOPE, 1972; 1983 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 229)
    - Quakers, 1961-1982 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 230)
    - Retired Public Employees' Association, 1979-1984 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 231)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Memorial Fund, 1963 (Box 23 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 232)
    - Sakharov, Andrei, Defense Campaign, 1980-1981 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 233)
    - San Francisco International Program for Youth Leaders and Social Workers, Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 234)
    - San Jose Peace Center, 1984 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 235)
    - SANE, 1977; 1980 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 236)
    - Save San Francisco Bay Association, 1963-1981 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 237)
    - Save the Children International Union/Union Internationale de Secours aux Enfants, 1940 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 238)
    - * Schweizerische Gemeinnützige Gesellschaft, Undated
      See Rickenbach, Walter
    - Schweizerische Gesellschaft für Präventivmedizin, 1965-1980 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 239)
    - Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc. (Fred S. Weissman), 1939-1966 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 240)
    - Selfhelp of Chicago, Inc./Selfhelp Home for the Aged, Inc., 1960-1983 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 241)
    - Smithsonian Institution, Undated (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 242)
    - Social Democrats / Young Social Democrats, 1978-1983 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 243)
    - Social Security Administration, 1949 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 244)
    - Social Service Administration Club, 1939 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 245)
    - Social Service Bureau of the East Bay, Inc., 1983 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 246)
    - Social Welfare History Group, 1975 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 247)
    - Social Workers' Non-Partisan Committee for Roosevelt, 1944 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 248)
    - Socialist Party, 1937 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 249)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems, 1959-1984 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 250)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems (A-C), 1963-1965 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 251)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems (D-K), 1963-1965 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 252)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems (L-M), 1963-1965 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 253)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems (N-Z), 1963-1965 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 254)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems, Committee on Poverty and Human Resources (Louis A. Ferman), 1965-1966 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 255)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems -- memos, programs, Undated (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 256)
    - Society for the Study of Social Problems -- membership lists, Undated (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 257)
    - SOS Children's Town, Austria / SOS-Kinderdörfer, 1961-1983 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 258)
    - Sozialistische Jugend Deutschlands / Die Falken, 1984 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 259)
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign, 1939 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 260)
    - Sproul (Gordon & Ida) Scholarship Fund, 1958 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 261)
    - St. Labre Indian School, Undated (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 262)
    - Stanley Foundation, 1981 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 263)
    - Study Abroad, Inc. -- Munich conference arrangements, 1954-1956 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 264)
    - Study Abroad, Inc. -- Rome conference arrangements, 1959-1961 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 265)
    - Study Abroad, Inc. -- Athens conference arrangements, 1963-1964 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 266)
    - Study Abroad, Inc., 1966-1970 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 267)
    - Study Group on Social Change and Correctional Services, 1965-1966 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 268)
    - The Summer School of Painting at Saugatuck, Michigan, 1940 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 269)
    - Swedish International Development Society, 1978 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 270)
    - Twin Cities International Program for Youth Leaders and Social Workers, 1964 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 271)
    - UNESCO, 1978-1981 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 272)
      See also Hackbarth, Dorothy.
    - UNICEF (Norman Acton; Mrs. Carter Collins; Irma-Lotte Haesler-Oeser; Gräfin von Rantzau), 1955-1983 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 273)
    - Unitarian Service Committee, Undated (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 274)
    - United Farm Workers, 1973 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 275)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America, 1947-1983 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 276)
    - United States Committee for Refugees, 1981 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 277)
    - U. S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare/Federal Security Agency (Dorothy Lally; Elisabeth Shirley Enochs), 1951-1982 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 278)
    - U. S. Educational Commission in the Federal Republic of Germany (Fulbright Commission), 1958 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 279)
    - United States High Commissioner for Germany (HICOG), 1952 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 280)
    - United States Purchasing Exchange, 1982-1984 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 281)
    - United World Federalists, 1963-1969 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 282)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1946-1983 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 283)
    - University of California, Berkeley -- YMCA/YWCA -- Stiles Hall, 1960-1976 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 284)
    - University of Chicago, 1939-1978 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 285)
    - University of Minnesota (John C. Kidneigh), 1963-1964 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 286)
    - University of Southern California, 1948 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 287)
    - UNRRA, 1945-1948 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 288)
    - Verein Sozialistischer Aerzte, 1931 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 289)
    - Victor Gollancz-Stiftung, 1972 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 290)
    - Vienna Institute for Development, 1978 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 291)
    - Vietnam Moratorium Committee, Undated (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 292)
    - Weltkomitee für die Opfer des Hitlerfaschismus, 1933 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 293)
    - Wiesenthal, Simon, Center, 1981; Undated (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 294)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1974 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 295)
    - World Affairs Council of Northern California, 1947 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 296)
    - World Conference on Agricultural Reform, 1979 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 297)
    - World Federalists Association, 1980-1984 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 298)
    - World Federation for Mental Health, 1959-1977 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 299)
    - World Health Organization, 1977 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 300)
    - World Without War Council, 1975 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 301)
    - * Young Social Democrats, Undated
      See Social Democrats.
    - Youth Institute for Peace in the Middle East, 1982-1984 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 302)
    - Zweites Deutsches Fernsehen (ZDF), 1980 (Box 24 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 303)
  - Correspondence with politicians and public officials, 1950-1984; 2.5; 127 folders, approx. 592 items of correspondence
    A substantial amount of the correspondence in this section consists of form letters and newsletters sent to Friedländer by politicians seeking election to various public offices.
    - Abzug, Bella, 1977 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 1)
      (form letter).
    - Allen, John J., Jr., 1950 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 2)
    - Altmaier, Jakob, 1959-1960 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 3)
    - Bach, Otto, 1952-1953 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 4)
    - Bates, Thomas H. (Tom), 1972-1982 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 5)
      (mostly form letters, newsletters).
    - Berger, Liselotte, 1975 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 6)
    - Brandt, Willy, 1952-1983 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 7)
    - Brown, Edmund G., 1961-1970 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 8)
    - Burton, John L., 1968-1974 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 9)
    - Burton, Phillip, 1980 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
    - Byrd, R. (Senator), 1963 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 11)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1977 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 12)
    - Church, Frank, 1971 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 13)
    - Citron, Klaus J. (Generalkonsul), 1963-1966 (Box 25 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 14)